duke-energy.com 2019-12-16

# Privacy Policy - Duke Energy

Your session will expire in {{countBack}} seconds, please select OK to continue your session

  * The types of personal information we may obtain about you through our Digital Services include:  

    * contact information (such as name, phone and fax number, email address and mailing and service address);  
    * information used to create your online account and other account-related information (such as username, password, security questions and answers, account number, and any content you choose to store in your account);  
    * demographic information, such as date of birth, gender and other background information (such as your ethnicity if you inquire about programs applicable to minorities);  
    * Social Security number, driver’s license number, tax identification number and other government-issued identification numbers;  
    * payment information, such as name, billing address, bank account information, and payment card details (including payment card number, expiration date and security code), some of which is collected and stored by our third-party payment processor on our behalf;  
    * information related to your transactions with us, such as your payment history;  
    * social media handles; and  
    * other personal information in content you submit to us, such as information you provide to us when you create or modify your online account, contact us through emails or our Digital Services, respond to surveys, use our forums, and complete any registration or self-service transaction forms.  

We may obtain some information about you from third parties. For example, during the Start Service process, Duke Energy supplements the information you provide through our Digital Services with additional data received from third-party sources. We also may supplement your information with additional information we receive from a credit check performed when you apply for certain services. This information helps us to verify, update and correct the information our customers provide to us and enables us to determine if a deposit will be needed to provide you with services.  

  We also may collect other information about you through our Digital Services in ways for which we provide specific notice or otherwise with your consent.  

_Automated Collection of Data  _

  When you interact with our Digital Services or open our emails, we may obtain certain information by automated means, such as browser cookies, web beacons, device identifiers, server logs, and other technologies. A “browser cookie” is a text file that we save on your device when you use our Digital Services. Cookies allow us to uniquely identify users and to store information or settings. A “web beacon,” also known as an Internet tag, pixel tag or clear GIF, is a clear picture file that allows us and third parties to store information about your interactions with our Digital Services, such as how you use the Digital Services and view our content.  

  We may use these automated technologies to collect information about your devices, browsing actions, and usage patterns. The information we obtain in this manner may include your device IP address, Internet service provider, identifiers associated with your devices, domain name, device and operating system type and characteristics, web browser characteristics, language preferences, information about your interactions with and preferences on our Digital Services (such as clickstream data), the webpage from which you link to or from our Digital Services, dates and times of access to our Digital Services, and other information about your use of our Digital Services. These technologies help us (1) remember your information so you will not have to re-enter it; (2) track and understand how you use and interact with our Digital Services; (3) tailor our Digital Services around your preferences; (4) measure the usability of our Digital Services; (5) understand the effectiveness of our communications; (6) identify, diagnose and resolve technical issues; and (7) otherwise manage and enhance our Digital Services (and our other products and services) and help ensure they are working properly. 

  You can manage cookies through your web browser. Most web browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new browser cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new browser cookie and how to disable existing cookies. You can find out how to do this for your particular browser by clicking “help” on your browser’s menu or by visiting [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). In addition, your mobile device settings may allow you to prohibit mobile app platforms (such as Apple and Google) from sharing certain information obtained by automated means with mobile app developers and operators such as us. Please note, however, that without cookies and similar technologies we use, you may not be able to take full advantage of all features of our Digital Services. Our Digital Services currently do not respond to “Do Not Track” signals.  

  We also may receive your mobile device’s precise geolocation. We may use this information to provide you with location-based services, such as to assist you with finding a nearby payment location. This information is not stored by us for future use. Your device may provide you with a notification when the Digital Services attempt to collect your precise geolocation. Location services can be turned off within the settings of your mobile device.

  * We may use the information we obtain about you to: 

    * provide and manage our services, including to process, evaluate, communicate and fulfill requests, inquiries and claims we receive in connection with our services;  
    * create, manage, administer and communicate with you about your account, including identifying and authenticating you so you may access your account or use certain features of our Digital Services;  
    * personalize your experience with our Digital Services (such as to tailor content and information we may communicate to you, and to offer location-based and personalized content and communications);  
    * provide customer and technical support; 
    * process, evaluate and respond to requests, inquiries and applications we receive in connection with our services; 
    * provide you with information about Duke Energy; 
    * subject to applicable law, communicate about and administer our services, events, surveys, programs and promotions (such as by sending alerts, promotional materials, newsletters and other marketing communications); 
    * perform data analytics (such as crash analytics, offer acceptance rates, market research, trend analysis, data aggregation and anonymization, financial analysis and customer segmentation); 
    * operate, evaluate and improve our business (including administering, enhancing and improving our services; developing new services; managing our communications and customer relationships; and performing accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation and collection activities);  
    * protect against and prevent fraud and other unlawful activity, unauthorized transactions, claims and other liabilities;  
    * conduct investigations and comply with and enforce applicable legal requirements, relevant industry standards, contractual obligations, and our policies and terms (such as our privacy policies and Terms of Use); and  
    * maintain and enhance the safety and security of our services, network, information, customers, employees and others. 

We also may use the information we obtain about you in other ways for which we provide specific notice and obtain your consent if required by applicable law. We may combine information we obtain about you (such as through our Digital Services or from third parties) for the purposes described above.  

  _Third-Party Online Analytics Services  _

  Through our Digital Services, we may obtain personal information about your online activities over time and across third-party apps, websites, devices and other online services. We use third-party online analytics services on our Digital Services, such as those of Google Analytics. The service providers that administer these analytics services use automated technologies to collect data (such as email, IP addresses, cookies and other device identifiers) to evaluate, for example, use of our Digital Services and to diagnose technical issues. For more information about how Google Analytics collects and processes data and the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, please visit <https://policies.google.com/privacy#infocollect> and <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>. 

  In our Digital Services, we may use certain Google Analytics advertising features, such as Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, and integrated services that require Google Analytics to collect data for advertising purposes, including the collection of data via advertising cookies and identifiers. In connection with these Google Analytics advertising features, Google Analytics may collect data about your traffic via Google advertising cookies and identifiers. To learn more about how Google uses this information, please visit [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). If you do not want Google Analytics to use this information for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt out of certain Google Analytics advertising features by visiting the Google Ads Settings page available at <https://adssettings.google.com/>. 

  _Online Tracking and Interest-Based Advertising  _

  Through our Digital Services, both we and certain third parties may collect information about your online activities to provide you with advertising about products, services and corporate initiatives tailored to your individual interests. Where required by applicable law, we will obtain your consent for the processing of your personal information for direct marketing purposes. You may see our ads on other websites or mobile apps because we participate in advertising networks. Ad networks allow us to target our messaging to users considering demographic data, users’ inferred interests and browsing context. These networks track users’ online activities over time by collecting information through automated means, including through the use of browser cookies, web beacons, device identifiers, server logs and other similar technologies. The networks use this information to show ads that may be tailored to individuals’ interests, to track users’ browsers or devices across multiple websites and apps, and to build a profile of users’ online browsing and app usage activities. The information our ad networks may collect includes data about users’ visits to websites and apps that participate in the relevant ad networks, such as the pages or ads viewed and the actions taken on the websites or apps. This data collection takes place both on our Digital Services and on third-party websites and apps that participate in the ad networks. This process also helps us track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. 

  To learn how to opt out of ad network interest-based advertising in the U.S., please visit [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) and <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>. 

  * We do not sell or otherwise share personal information about you except as described in this Digital Privacy Policy.  

    * Subject to applicable law, we may share your personal information with our affiliates and subsidiaries for the purposes described in this Digital Privacy Policy. 
    * We may share your personal information with service providers who perform services for us or on our behalf, such as those related to payment processing, database and web hosting, email service providers, map service providers, sweepstakes administrators, credit reporting agencies, advertising and marketing, electronic bill payment services or debt collection, data analytics and administrative or management functions. We do not authorize these service providers to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. 
    * We may share your information with third parties who are providing the product, service or information that you have requested.  
    * With your consent, we also may share your information with third parties who may send you promotional materials and marketing communications about products and services that may be of interest to you. 
    * We may disclose personal information about you (1) if we are required to do so by law or legal process (such as a court order or subpoena), (2) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials to comply with legal requests, (3) when we believe disclosure is necessary to prevent physical harm or financial loss, (4) to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights, (5) in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual fraud or illegal activity or (6) otherwise with your consent. 

We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event of a potential or actual sale or transfer of all or a portion of our business or assets (including in the event of a merger, acquisition, joint venture, reorganization, divestiture, dissolution, liquidation or other corporate restructuring). 

  * Some state laws, and certain state utility commissions with regulatory oversight of our utility service territories, require that certain customer information be protected from disclosure to our affiliate companies. The relevant laws and codes of conduct may be found here:

    * [Florida: Rule No. 25-6.014](https://www.flrules.org/gateway/RuleNo.asp?title=ELECTRIC%20SERVICE%20BY%20ELECTRIC%20PUBLIC%20UTILITIES&ID=25-6.014) and [Rule No. 25-6.015](https://www.flrules.org/gateway/RuleNo.asp?title=ELECTRIC%20SERVICE%20BY%20ELECTRIC%20PUBLIC%20UTILITIES&ID=25-6.015)

Duke Energy administers role-based training that addresses various regulatory requirements for employees and contingent workers in all regulated jurisdictions on a monthly and annual basis. Employees and contingent workers receive training on corporate separation requirements, proper handling of customer information, marketing non-regulated products and services, asset transfers, affiliate transaction restrictions, and time reporting, in addition to other subjects required by a regulated jurisdiction.  

  * We offer you certain choices in connection with the personal information we obtain about you. To update your preferences, limit the communications you receive from us or submit a request, please contact us as specified in the How to Contact Us section of this Digital Privacy Policy or adjust the privacy settings in the Digital Service, as applicable.  

  You will receive email communications from us in connection with your use of our Digital Services and other services, such as when you sign up for an account online, perform an online transaction (for example, paying your bill or requesting a new password) or provide your email address to a customer contact representative. You may also receive email communications from us about new products and services. To opt out of receiving marketing emails from us, use the one-click unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email you received. In some instances, Duke Energy will co-brand with another company. Please be aware that the privacy policy referenced at the bottom of the webpage governs the collection of information on that page. 

  * Our Digital Services may transfer you to or provide links to third-party websites or provide you access to certain third-party features (such as the ability to view third-party videos and content or connect to certain social networks or third-party services through our Digital Services) for your convenience and to provide selected services or functions. These third-party websites and features may use cookies to collect information on our sites, including via plug-ins and widgets. These third parties may operate independently from us. The privacy practices of the relevant third parties, including details on the information they may collect about you, are subject to the privacy statements of these parties, which we strongly suggest you review. To the extent any linked services or third-party features are not owned or controlled by us, Duke Energy is not responsible for these third parties’ information practices.   

  * **Subject to certain limits under California law, California residents may ask us to provide them with (1) a list of certain categories of personal information we have disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, and (2) the identity of those third parties.   To make this request, California residents may contact us as specified in the How to Contact Us section below.**  

  * We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect personal information against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use. 

  * Certain of Duke Energy's Digital Services are directed to children and teens located in the United States, including children under age 13. We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from children under age 13 without parental consent, unless permitted by law. If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without parental consent or unless otherwise permitted by law, we will delete it in accordance with applicable law. If you believe that a child may have provided us with personal information without parental consent or otherwise not permitted by law, please contact us as specified in the How to Contact Us section of this Digital Privacy Policy.  

  Duke Energy is committed to protecting the privacy of children who use our Digital Services. This Section of the Digital Privacy Policy explains our information practices in the United States with respect to information provided by children under the age of 13. Please note that this Section of the Digital Privacy Policy applies regardless of whether your child uses a computer, mobile phone, tablet, or other device to access our Digital Services. 

 **WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?  **  
_Information your child provides directly  _  
Some Duke Energy Digital Services enable your child to give us information directly. For example, your child may be asked to provide the email address of his or her parent or guardian in connection with registering for a Digital Service. With your consent, we may combine the parental email address information we collect from your child with information about your Duke Energy customer account. 

  _Information about your child’s use of the Digital Services  _  
We may also collect information about your child’s use of our Digital Services through software on the device your child uses and other means. For example, we may collect: 

    * **Log information** \- such as the time and duration of your child’s use of the Digital Service, and any information stored in cookies that we have set on the device. 
    * **Device information** \- such as the hardware model, IMEI number and other unique device identifiers, MAC address, IP address, operating system versions, and settings. 
    * **Other information** about your child’s use of the Digital Services, such as how your child interacts with content offered through a Service. 

**HOW DO WE USE YOUR CHILD’S INFORMATION?  **  
We may use information we collect from your child for the following purposes: 

    * to provide a Digital Service or feature your child requests; 
    * to notify and communicate with you, the child’s parent or guardian, about your child’s use of the Digital Service; 
    * to provide customized content and provide personalized services based on your child’s past activities on our Digital Services; 
    * for assessment and analysis of our market, customers, products, and services; and 
    * to understand the way people use our Digital Services so that we can improve them and develop new products and services.  

**TO WHOM DO WE DISCLOSE YOUR INFORMATION?  **  
We will not disclose information collected from your child to third parties for their own independent marketing or business purposes without your further consent. However, we may disclose such information to the following entities: 

    * **Service providers**. We may disclose the information collected from your child to companies that provide services for or on behalf of us, such as companies that help our Digital Services to function. These entities are limited in their ability to use the information collected from your child for purposes other than providing services for us. 
    * **Other Parties When Required by Law or as Necessary to Protect Our Services**. There may be instances when we disclose information collected from your child to other parties:  
      1. to comply with the law or respond to compulsory legal process (such as a search warrant or other court order); 
      2. to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our Digital Services; and 
      3. to protect the rights, property, or safety of Duke Energy Corporation, or any of our respective affiliates, business partners, or customers. 
    * **Other Parties in Connection with Corporate Transactions**. We may disclose information collected from your child to a third party as part of a merger or transfer, or in the event of a bankruptcy. 

**DATA RETENTION AND DELETION  **  
As a parent or guardian, you can review or have the information collected from your child deleted. You may also refuse to permit further collection or use of the information. To do so, please email our Data Privacy Program at [dataprivacy@duke-energy.com](mailto:dataprivacy@duke-energy.com) or contact us using the information below.  

  * This Digital Privacy Policy may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal information practices. We will indicate at the top of the policy when it was most recently updated.  

  * If you have any questions about this Digital Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, or if you would like us to update information we have about you, change your preferences or exercise other applicable privacy rights, please email our Data Privacy Program at [dataprivacy@duke-energy.com](mailto:dataprivacy@duke-energy.com) or contact us using the information below:

  | Duke Energy | Duke Energy Progress  
---|---|---  
General  
Correspondence  
Address  
_Not for customer  
account inquiries  
or payments_ | 550 S. Tryon Street  
Charlotte, NC 28202 | P.O. Box 1771  
Raleigh, NC 27602  
Customer  
Service  
Email/Web | 

| 

Customer  
Service  
Telephone | 

Carolinas - [800.777.9898](tel:800.777.9898)  
Florida - [800.700.8744](tel:800.700.8744)  
Indiana - [800.521.2232](tel:800.521.2232)  
Ohio and Kentucky - [800.544.6900](tel:800.544.6900)

| Carolinas - [800.452.2777](tel:800.452.2777)
